<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Corey&#39;s VBD Research</title>
    <link>https://www.Corey-Day.com/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://www.Corey-Day.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Corey&#39;s VBD Research</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2030 13:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://www.Corey-Day.com/media/logo_hu7d4e0e7e1d4a3a6826d7b8a27c541b87_61713_300x300_fit_lanczos_3.png</url>
      <title>Corey&#39;s VBD Research</title>
      <link>https://www.Corey-Day.com/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Example Talk</title>
      <link>https://www.Corey-Day.com/talk/example-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2030 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.Corey-Day.com/talk/example-talk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Click on the &lt;strong&gt;Slides&lt;/strong&gt; button above to view the built-in slides feature.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides can be added in a few ways:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create&lt;/strong&gt; slides using Wowchemy&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/managing-content/#create-slides&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Slides&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; feature and link using &lt;code&gt;slides&lt;/code&gt; parameter in the front matter of the talk file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Upload&lt;/strong&gt; an existing slide deck to &lt;code&gt;static/&lt;/code&gt; and link using &lt;code&gt;url_slides&lt;/code&gt; parameter in the front matter of the talk file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Embed&lt;/strong&gt; your slides (e.g. Google Slides) or presentation video on this page using &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;shortcodes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further event details, including &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;page elements&lt;/a&gt; such as image galleries, can be added to the body of this page.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spatial-Temporal Clusters of La Crosse Virus Disease </title>
      <link>https://www.Corey-Day.com/project/spatial-temporal-clusters-of-la-crosse-virus-disease/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.Corey-Day.com/project/spatial-temporal-clusters-of-la-crosse-virus-disease/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Example of county-level La Crosse virus disease clusters. Counties in dark blue were in high-risk clusters from 2003 to 2021.  &#34; srcset=&#34;
               /project/spatial-temporal-clusters-of-la-crosse-virus-disease/images/TN_NC_Clusters_hu3ec7a8dce5c6f6f6524fe0e6cf894130_246871_e1c0f5f2c80ea5ccf04162861764d230.webp 400w,
               /project/spatial-temporal-clusters-of-la-crosse-virus-disease/images/TN_NC_Clusters_hu3ec7a8dce5c6f6f6524fe0e6cf894130_246871_aaa1e72358dea554a4e72d0c4af3ed1e.webp 760w,
               /project/spatial-temporal-clusters-of-la-crosse-virus-disease/images/TN_NC_Clusters_hu3ec7a8dce5c6f6f6524fe0e6cf894130_246871_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://www.Corey-Day.com/project/spatial-temporal-clusters-of-la-crosse-virus-disease/images/TN_NC_Clusters_hu3ec7a8dce5c6f6f6524fe0e6cf894130_246871_e1c0f5f2c80ea5ccf04162861764d230.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;535&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part of my PhD research focuses on the geographic epidemiology of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.corey-day.com/research-posts/what-is-la-crosse-virus-disease/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;La Crosse virus disease&lt;/a&gt;, which is a mosquito borne disease that primarily affects children. Prior to my research, there was some evidence that La Crosse virus risk was spatially persistent, meaning that if there is high risk at one location right now, that location will continue to have high risk in the future. If that pattern of spatial persistence is true, then it will be important for future efforts to prevent La Crosse virus infections. Hopefully, we can use the results of this research to find the places where people are most likely to become infected so that we can prevent more children from getting sick.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a need for formal epidemiological analyses using spatial tools to investigate the spatial patterns of La Crosse virus disease. My hypothesis is that the geographic distribution of La Crosse virus disease has remained consistent in the last two decades. To test that hypothesis, I am conducting high-risk disease cluster analyses on multiple geographic scales. First, I am using publicly available data from the United States&amp;rsquo; arboviral disease database, ArboNET, to investigate disease clustering at the county level in the eastern United States. A county-level disease cluster is a group of neighboring counties that have significantly higher La Crosse virus disease risk than the eastern United States overall. Prior to my work, only one study has investigated La Crosse virus disease clustering at this scale, using data from 2003 to 2007. I repeated the analysis for that time period and additionally investigating clustering in subsequent time periods to compare the distribution of high-risk clusters from 2003 to 2021. This research is currently under peer review, and I will update this page with a link to the open access article once it is published. For now, here is a hint: disease risk has remained persistent in a few clusters of counties for nearly 20 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will also conduct a fine-scale investigation of risk clustering in partnership with the North Carolina Department of Health and Human Services. North Carolina has some of the highest rates of La Crosse virus disease in the country, and the vast majority of that disease is reported from a few counties in western NC. Whilst ensuring that the privacy of individuals is protected, I will conduct a household-level cluster investigation using the home addresses of all reported La Crosse virus disease in North Carolina from 1997 to 2020. My hypothesis is that the addresses will not be randomly distributed throughout the high-risk counties, but instead that the houses are often clustered together. If that is true, then this work will identify specific areas where people consistently become infected with La Crosse virus, and public health officials can target their prevention efforts directly to those places. This might include virus surveillance, mosquito control, and awareness campaigns to help people protect their children from La Crosse virus disease.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using &#39;rflexscan&#39; to detect flexibly-shaped disease clusters with R </title>
      <link>https://www.Corey-Day.com/r-tutorials/using-rflexscan-to-detect-flexibly-shaped-disease-clusters-with-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.Corey-Day.com/r-tutorials/using-rflexscan-to-detect-flexibly-shaped-disease-clusters-with-r/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;div id=&#34;TOC&#34;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#assumptions&#34;&gt;Assumptions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#installing-the-necessary-packages&#34;&gt;Installing the necessary packages&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;introduction&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scan statistics are commonly used in epidemiology for detecting geographic clusters of disease. The most common is Kulldorf’s circular scan statistic (used with SatScan software), which identifies circularly-shaped clusters. A lesser-known but powerful scan statistic is Tango’s flexibly-shaped scan statistic (FSSS), which identifies “flexibly-shaped” clusters. This simply means that instead of only identifying clusters in a circular form, the flexible scan statistic can identify clusters of any shape. This is useful in the myriad scenarios where clusters are not likely to literally form a circle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most straight-forward way to use Tango’s FSSS is with the freely-available &lt;a href=&#34;https://sites.google.com/site/flexscansoftware/download_e&#34;&gt;FlexScan software&lt;/a&gt;, which works similarly to SatScan. FlexScan works well, but as with most click-based software, using it for large workloads becomes cumbersome, and issues with replication may arise. Queue &lt;code&gt;rflexscan&lt;/code&gt;, the R package that implements Tango’s FSSS. This package can do everything that FlexScan does, with the benefit of reproducible R code that can be converted into functions and loops for large projects. Additionally, by working in R, you have access to the plethora of R packages for spatial analysis, allowing you to complete most (or all) of your workflow in a single environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The downside to &lt;code&gt;rflexscan&lt;/code&gt; is that it is not well-documented online. &lt;a href=&#34;https://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/rflexscan/rflexscan.pdf&#34;&gt;The user manual&lt;/a&gt; is a good starting point, but is probably not enough to get inexperienced users going. Because the FSSS is not so commonly used, &lt;code&gt;rflexscan&lt;/code&gt; also seems to lack user-made tutorials that are so helpful for other R packages. With that issue in mind, I am creating this tutorial that will help people use &lt;code&gt;rflexscan&lt;/code&gt; to detect flexibly-shaped disease clusters. I will walk through an example from beginning-to-end, relying entirely on R and its helpful packages to create a reproducible workflow. I hope that this will help the next person who wants to use this package!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;assumptions&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Assumptions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am going to assume basic R knowledge, including knowledge of the &lt;code&gt;tidyverse&lt;/code&gt; family of packages for data manipulation. If you struggle to understand any data manipulation in this article, I highly recommend visting &lt;a href=&#34;https://ourcodingclub.github.io/tutorials.html&#34;&gt;Our Coding Club&lt;/a&gt; and working through their data manipulation tutorials. The skills gained from those tutorials can drastically improve your efficiency when working with data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;installing-the-necessary-packages&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Installing the necessary packages&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am going to rely on a few different packages for this tutorial: &lt;code&gt;rflexscan&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;spdep&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;sf&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;tidyverse&lt;/code&gt;. Each of these packages are excellent for spatial analysis, so installing them should be worthwhile for you. If you have not installed them, use &lt;code&gt;install.packages(&#39;insert_package_name_here&#39;)&lt;/code&gt;. Once they are installed, use the code below to load them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;library(rflexscan)
library(spdep)
library(sf)
library(tidyverse)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is La Crosse Virus Disease?</title>
      <link>https://www.Corey-Day.com/research-posts/what-is-la-crosse-virus-disease/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.Corey-Day.com/research-posts/what-is-la-crosse-virus-disease/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;script src=&#34;https://www.Corey-Day.com/research-posts/what-is-la-crosse-virus-disease/index.en_files/header-attrs/header-attrs.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;images/LACV_vectors.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fig 1.&lt;/strong&gt; The La Crosse virus vectors: &lt;em&gt;Aedes triseriatus&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Aedes albopictus&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Aedes japonicus&lt;/em&gt; (photos from BugGuide.net)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;have-you-heard-of-la-crosse-virus&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Have you heard of La Crosse virus?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even within the world of mosquito-borne disease researchers, few people actively study La Crosse virus. Outside of that world, I have met extremely few people who had ever heard of La Crosse virus at all. That fact is disconcerting to me, because I have spent my entire life residing in Appalachia, where more people are infected with La Crosse virus than anywhere else in the world. Every summer, children in Appalachia will develop a mysterious flu-likely illness that quickly begins to cause seizures, and possibly even comas. Some of those children will develop neurological disabilities that hinder them for years. For most of those children and their parents, their diagnosis will be the first time they learn about La Crosse virus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My goal for this post is to produce a short, reader-friendly description of La Crosse virus disease (often called La Crosse encephalitis). Everything I write will be based on peer-reviewed scientific evidence, although I will not provide a full references list as I would in a scientific manuscript. I encourage interested parties to also visit the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cdc.gov/lac/index.html&#34;&gt;CDC’s official website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;the-impact-of-la-crosse-virus-disease&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;The impact of La Crosse virus disease&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La Crosse virus (LACV) is transmitted by mosquitoes and it is the second-most common cause of mosquito-borne disease in the United States. Most of the time, when a human is exposed to LACV, they will never know that it happened. Sometimes (we really don’t know how often), a LACV infection causes a generic, flu-like illness that will probably never be diagnosed. Less often (but more often than reported), LACV infects the central nervous system, causing neuroinvasive disease. More than 90% of all LACV disease occurs in children aged 18 years and younger. This is thought to be because young individuals have reduced capacities to prevent LACV infection from reaching the nervous system. Regardless of age, LACV infections are rarely fatal, but often have severe long-term effects. Neuroinvasive LACV infections are usually called La Crosse encephalitis (LACE), because the infection regularly causes encephalitis (i.e., inflammation of the brain). However, neuroinvasive LACV infections may instead result in meningitis (infection of membranes surrounding the brain) or meningoencephalitis (a combination of encephalitis and meningitis) &lt;span class=&#34;citation&#34;&gt;[see &lt;a href=&#34;#ref-mcjunkinCrosseEncephalitisChildren2001&#34; role=&#34;doc-biblioref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt; for research on the health effects of LACV disease on children]&lt;/span&gt;. Symptoms of LACV infection initially include headaches, vomiting, and fatigue, and severe neuroinvasive cases often lead to seizures. Severe cases can also cause chronic seizure disorders, partial paralysis of the body, and lifelong cognitive disabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neuroinvasive LACV disease often requires hospitalization, likely in a specialized pediatric hospital. There is no defined treatment for LACV disease, so medical professionals can only provide supportive treatments. The financial costs of treatment, time taken off work for parents, and travel to and from hospitals can be extreme. Worse, because many cases of severe LACV disease cause lifelong neurological disabilities, there are additional costs associated with the disease even after the primary treatment has ended. A study from 2003 found that the total cost of neuroinvasive LACV disease for children who have lifelong consequences could exceed $3 million &lt;span class=&#34;citation&#34;&gt;[see &lt;a href=&#34;#ref-utzEconomicSocialImpacts2003&#34; role=&#34;doc-biblioref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt; for research on economic impacts of LACV disease in North Carolina]&lt;/span&gt;. Few families are prepared for this type of financial burden, especially in the economically disadvantaged Appalachian region, where most LACV disease occurrs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;where-is-the-risk&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Where is the risk?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;images/La%20Crosse%20cases%202003%20to%202021.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fig 2. &lt;/strong&gt; Map of neuroinvasive La Crosse virus disease cases in the eastern United States from 2003 to 2021 (data from ArboNET; map author: Corey Day)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the grand scheme of things, LACV disease is rare. For the entire United States, fewer than 100 cases of LACV disease are diagnosed each year, but that statistic misses the bigger (or smaller?) picture: a small group of people bear most of the burden of LACV diseases. LACV infection risk depends heavily on where one lives, and almost every case of LACV disease is associated with a few high-risk areas in either Appalachia or the upper Midwest. Consistently, LACV disease occurs in the same regions in a select number of counties. The highest risks by-far are for children living in western North Carolina, east Tennessee, West Virginia, and Ohio (see Fig. 2 for the case distribution of LACV disease from 2003 to 2021). In 2018, researchers in North Carolina realized that not only does LACV disease consistently occur in the same counties, but it also occurs at the &lt;em&gt;same households&lt;/em&gt;. In some cases, this meant that multiple children living at one house became sick during the same year. Surprisingly, they also found that people were also becoming sick at the same household &lt;em&gt;in different years&lt;/em&gt;. The most extreme example of this was two cases of LACV disease that occurred 7 years apart, with ownership of the home being transferred during that 7-year period &lt;span class=&#34;citation&#34;&gt;[&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-byrdSpatiallyAssociatedCoincident2018&#34; role=&#34;doc-biblioref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;. Additionally, LACV disease is thought to be heavily under reported; cases of lesser severity are unlikely to be diagnosed, and the cases that we do see are just the “tip of the iceberg” in the high-risk areas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;what-is-being-done-about-that-risk&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;What is being done about that risk?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, we know that LACV disease consistently occurs in the same states, within the same counties, and even at the same households. This means that risk for this disease is extremely dependent on where a person lives. It also means that there is strong potential for health agencies to target areas with high persistent risks to prevent this disease. So, what is being done about it? The honest answer is &lt;strong&gt;“not much”&lt;/strong&gt;. I am not aware of any major public efforts to prevent LACV disease. There are small groups, including the research group I work in, who are attempting to develop outreach programs to raise awareness for this disease in high-risk areas &lt;span class=&#34;citation&#34;&gt;[&lt;a href=&#34;#ref-troutfryxellDevelopmentCommunitydrivenMosquito2022&#34; role=&#34;doc-biblioref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;, but that is really the extent of it. That is really a shame, because it is very possible that with resources and effort, we could identify the places where children are going to become infected with LACV, and prevent them from the serious effects those infections can have. &lt;a href=&#34;https://wwwnc.cdc.gov/eid/article/26/5/19-1606_article&#34;&gt;That sort of thing was accomplished during the Zika virus outbreak in 2016&lt;/a&gt;, and could also be done for LACV.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;how-can-you-protect-yourself&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;How can you protect yourself?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you live in a county where LACV disease occurs or are traveling to a high-risk area (e.g., a trip to Great Smoky Mountains National Park), &lt;strong&gt;especially if you have children&lt;/strong&gt;, I think that you should take LACV risk seriously. Because this is a mosquito-borne disease, the most definitive way to avoid it is to avoid bites from mosquitoes, which we all should want to do anyway regardless of where we are. If you live in the area, the first step you should take is to reduce mosquito habitat on your property. The vectors of LACV (see Fig 1) all use human-made containers which hold standing water as habitats for egg-laying and larval development. If you have containers in your yard (e.g., a wheel barrow, bird bath, used tires, buckets, childrens toys), then take a look for yourself in the summer. If you see little worms wiggling around, then you are watching mosquitoes develop. Having containers like that in your yard is a proven risk factor for LACV disease and other mosquito-borne diseases. Not to mention that you have more mosquitoes at your house than you need to. So, &lt;strong&gt;Step 1 is to tip and toss those containers&lt;/strong&gt;. You can also check gutters on your house; clogged gutters can make great mosquito habitats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even if you toss those containers, you will still encounter mosquitoes at your house and elsewhere. If you plan to spend time outdoors, the best way to protect yourself from mosquito bites is to apply an &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.epa.gov/insect-repellents/find-repellent-right-you&#34;&gt;EPA-approved repellent&lt;/a&gt;. Anything containing DEET is going to be effective. If you click the link to the EPA repellent site, you can use a search tool to find alternatives if DEET is not an option for you or your family. The good news about DEET-based repellents is that you will also be protected from ticks and other biting insects. Tick-borne diseases are no joke, so it is well-worth your efforts to protect yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;references&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;References&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;refs&#34; class=&#34;references csl-bib-body&#34;&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-mcjunkinCrosseEncephalitisChildren2001&#34; class=&#34;csl-entry&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;csl-left-margin&#34;&gt;1. &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;csl-right-inline&#34;&gt;McJunkin JE, De Los Reyes EC, Irazuzta JE, Caceres MJ, Khan RR, Minnich LL, et al. La &lt;span&gt;Crosse&lt;/span&gt; encephalitis in children. New England Journal of Medicine. 2001;344: 801–807. doi:&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1056/NEJM200103153441103&#34;&gt;10.1056/NEJM200103153441103&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-utzEconomicSocialImpacts2003&#34; class=&#34;csl-entry&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;csl-left-margin&#34;&gt;2. &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;csl-right-inline&#34;&gt;Utz JT, Apperson CS, Maccormack JN, Salyers M, Dietz EJ, Mcpherson JT. Economic and social impacts of &lt;span&gt;La Crosse&lt;/span&gt; encephalitis in western &lt;span&gt;North Carolina&lt;/span&gt;. American Journal of Tropical Medicine and Hygiene. 2003;69: 509–518. doi:&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.4269/ajtmh.2003.69.509&#34;&gt;10.4269/ajtmh.2003.69.509&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-byrdSpatiallyAssociatedCoincident2018&#34; class=&#34;csl-entry&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;csl-left-margin&#34;&gt;3. &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;csl-right-inline&#34;&gt;Byrd BD, Williams CJ, Staples EJ, Burkhalter KL, Savage HM, Doyle MS. Spatially associated coincident and noncoincident cases of &lt;span&gt;La Crosse&lt;/span&gt; encephalitis - &lt;span&gt;North Carolina&lt;/span&gt;, 2002-2017. Morbidity and Mortality Weekly Report. 2018;67: 1104–1105. Available: &lt;a href=&#34;http://dx.doi.org/10.15585/mmwr.mm6739a8&#34;&gt;http://dx.doi.org/10.15585/mmwr.mm6739a8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ref-troutfryxellDevelopmentCommunitydrivenMosquito2022&#34; class=&#34;csl-entry&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;csl-left-margin&#34;&gt;4. &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;csl-right-inline&#34;&gt;Trout Fryxell RT, Camponovo M, Smith B, Butefish K, Rosenberg JM, Andsager JL, et al. Development of a community-driven mosquito surveillance program for vectors of &lt;span&gt;La Crosse&lt;/span&gt; virus to educate, inform, and empower a community. Insects. 2022;13: 164. doi:&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3390/insects13020164&#34;&gt;10.3390/insects13020164&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slides</title>
      <link>https://www.Corey-Day.com/slides/example/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.Corey-Day.com/slides/example/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;create-slides-in-markdown-with-wowchemy&#34;&gt;Create slides in Markdown with Wowchemy&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Wowchemy&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;https://owchemy.com/docs/managing-content/#create-slides&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;features&#34;&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Efficiently write slides in Markdown&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3-in-1: Create, Present, and Publish your slides&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Supports speaker notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mobile friendly slides&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;controls&#34;&gt;Controls&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Next: &lt;code&gt;Right Arrow&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;Space&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Previous: &lt;code&gt;Left Arrow&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start: &lt;code&gt;Home&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finish: &lt;code&gt;End&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overview: &lt;code&gt;Esc&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Speaker notes: &lt;code&gt;S&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fullscreen: &lt;code&gt;F&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Zoom: &lt;code&gt;Alt + Click&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://revealjs.com/pdf-export/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;PDF Export&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;code-highlighting&#34;&gt;Code Highlighting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inline code: &lt;code&gt;variable&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Code block:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34; data-lang=&#34;python&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;porridge&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;s2&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;blueberry&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;porridge&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;==&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;s2&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;blueberry&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;    &lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;print&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s2&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;Eating...&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;math&#34;&gt;Math&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In-line math: $x + y = z$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Block math:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$$
f\left( x \right) = ;\frac{{2\left( {x + 4} \right)\left( {x - 4} \right)}}{{\left( {x + 4} \right)\left( {x + 1} \right)}}
$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;fragments&#34;&gt;Fragments&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make content appear incrementally&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;{{% fragment %}} One {{% /fragment %}}
{{% fragment %}} **Two** {{% /fragment %}}
{{% fragment %}} Three {{% /fragment %}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Press &lt;code&gt;Space&lt;/code&gt; to play!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;fragment &#34; &gt;
  One
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;fragment &#34; &gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;Two&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;fragment &#34; &gt;
  Three
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A fragment can accept two optional parameters:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;class&lt;/code&gt;: use a custom style (requires definition in custom CSS)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;weight&lt;/code&gt;: sets the order in which a fragment appears&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;speaker-notes&#34;&gt;Speaker Notes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add speaker notes to your presentation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-markdown&#34; data-lang=&#34;markdown&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;{{% speaker_note %}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; Only the speaker can read these notes
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; Press &lt;span class=&#34;sb&#34;&gt;`S`&lt;/span&gt; key to view
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;  {{% /speaker_note %}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Press the &lt;code&gt;S&lt;/code&gt; key to view the speaker notes!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Only the speaker can read these notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Press &lt;code&gt;S&lt;/code&gt; key to view&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;themes&#34;&gt;Themes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;black: Black background, white text, blue links (default)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;white: White background, black text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;league: Gray background, white text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;beige: Beige background, dark text, brown links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sky: Blue background, thin dark text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;night: Black background, thick white text, orange links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;serif: Cappuccino background, gray text, brown links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;simple: White background, black text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;solarized: Cream-colored background, dark green text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;section data-noprocess data-shortcode-slide
  
      
      data-background-image=&#34;/media/boards.jpg&#34;
  &gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;custom-slide&#34;&gt;Custom Slide&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Customize the slide style and background&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-markdown&#34; data-lang=&#34;markdown&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;{{&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;slide&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;na&#34;&gt;background-image&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;/media/boards.jpg&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;{{&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;slide&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;na&#34;&gt;background-color&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;#0000FF&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;{{&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;slide&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;na&#34;&gt;class&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;my-style&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;custom-css-example&#34;&gt;Custom CSS Example&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s make headers navy colored.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create &lt;code&gt;assets/css/reveal_custom.css&lt;/code&gt; with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-css&#34; data-lang=&#34;css&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nc&#34;&gt;reveal&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;section&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;h1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nc&#34;&gt;reveal&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;section&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;h2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nc&#34;&gt;reveal&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;section&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;h3&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;  &lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;color&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;kc&#34;&gt;navy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;questions&#34;&gt;Questions?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/wowchemy/wowchemy-hugo-modules/discussions&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Ask&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/managing-content/#create-slides&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy Policy</title>
      <link>https://www.Corey-Day.com/privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.Corey-Day.com/privacy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Add your privacy policy here and set &lt;code&gt;draft: false&lt;/code&gt; to publish it. Otherwise, delete this file if you don&amp;rsquo;t need it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terms</title>
      <link>https://www.Corey-Day.com/terms/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.Corey-Day.com/terms/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Add your terms here and set &lt;code&gt;draft: false&lt;/code&gt; to publish it. Otherwise, delete this file if you don&amp;rsquo;t need it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An example conference paper</title>
      <link>https://www.Corey-Day.com/publication/example/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.Corey-Day.com/publication/example/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Click the &lt;em&gt;Cite&lt;/em&gt; button above to demo the feature to enable visitors to import publication metadata into their reference management software.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Create your slides in Markdown - click the &lt;em&gt;Slides&lt;/em&gt; button to check out the example.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Supplementary notes can be added here, including &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;code, math, and images&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.Corey-Day.com/admin/config.yml</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.Corey-Day.com/admin/config.yml</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
